<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ACM REP 2026</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/</link><atom:link href="https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>ACM REP 2026</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/media/logo_hu5e52ed203217e8c1118e4c408d9ef1c8_43990_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>ACM REP 2026</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/</link></image><item><title>Attempt to rerun, reproduce and replicate Clinical Trials Sentence Classification Studies: lessons learnt</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/acceptedposters/dobrescu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/acceptedposters/dobrescu/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Experience with Reproducibility and Consistency in Writing an Academic Paper</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/acceptedposters/wonsil/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/acceptedposters/wonsil/</guid><description/></item><item><title>LLMs in Citation Intent Classification: Progress, Precision, and Reproducibility Challenges</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/acceptedposters/fogelson/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/acceptedposters/fogelson/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Posters</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/posters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/posters/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Toward a Systematic Assessment of Map Reproduction Success Using OCR</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/acceptedposters/mulaw/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/acceptedposters/mulaw/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sponsors</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/sponsor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/sponsor/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Travel &amp; Venue</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/venue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/venue/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Featured Keynote Speakers</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/keynotes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/keynotes/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/accepted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/accepted/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/cfp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/cfp/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/cfposters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/cfposters/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/cft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/cft/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Agenda</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/agenda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/agenda/</guid><description>&lt;iframe width="110%" height="3400px" style="border:none;" src="https://docs.google.com/document/d/e/2PACX-1vQBE2hiVfwgNrrVYNXnpWyUESNvJ4BvjXC4-gF-wT_CI7FzpLuG8rhTqT3fFYr-WtAmNY5zo3iNQKuQ/pub?embedded=true">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/conduct/</guid><description>&lt;p>The steering committee of ACM REP &amp;lsquo;24 believes in respect, compassion, understanding and inclusion and we expect all community members to act in accordance with these values. Fostering the free exchange of ideas requires building a conference that welcomes people of all backgrounds. Diversity of opinion and background is a fundamental strength of our community. The members of our community must have the freedom to espouse and explore a wide range of ideas. Toward that goal, ACM REP &amp;lsquo;24 aims to create spaces where every participant can express themselves without fear of judgment or harassment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ACM REP Code of Conduct guides the expected, professional behavior of conference participants, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Treating everyone with respect and consideration; under the umbrella of respect, we expect all participants to be mindful of their speech and behaviors both in person and online.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Communicating openly and thoughtfully with others and being considerate of the multitude of views and opinions that may be different than your own.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Being respectful and mindful in your critique of ideas.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Being mindful of your fellow participants, including (but not limited to):
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Respecting participants wishes to not be photographed;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Respecting participant gender pronouns; and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Respecting the space of others and their right to engage or not engage in conversation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We believe differences of opinion are a natural part of social and academic life and are important to work through when building community and learning from one another. At the same time, we acknowledge that societal power structures are even more challenging in academia, which is an inherently hierarchical community. In order to foster an environment of inclusion, we do not tolerate harassment, discrimination, or abuse in any form. Participants who engage in harassment may be removed from the conference at the discretion of the organizers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="unacceptable-behaviors-include-but-are-not-limited-to">Unacceptable behaviors include, but are not limited to:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>intimidating, harassing, abusive, discriminatory, derogatory or demeaning speech or actions by any participant in ACM-REP activities, at all related events and in one-on-one communications carried out in the context of conference activities;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>offensive, degrading, humiliating, harmful, or prejudicial verbal or written comments or visual images related to gender, sexual orientation, race, religion, disability, age, appearance, or other personal characteristics;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, or other verbal/physical conduct of a sexual nature;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>inappropriate or gratuitous use of nudity, sexual images, or stereotyped images including using an activity-related communication channel to display or distribute sexually explicit or otherwise offensive or discriminatory images or messages;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>deliberate intimidation, stalking or following;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>harassing photography or recording;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sustained disruption of talks or other events;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>unwelcome and uninvited attention or contact;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>physical assault (including unwelcome touch or groping);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>real or implied threat of physical harm;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>real or implied threat of professional or financial damage or harm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Harassment can occur when there is no deliberate intention to offend. Be careful in the words that you choose. Harassment committed in a joking manner or disguised as a compliment still constitutes unacceptable behavior. Remember that sexist, racist, and other exclusionary jokes can be offensive to those around you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="consequences-of-unacceptable-behavior">Consequences of Unacceptable Behavior&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If an ACM-REP participant engages in prohibited behavior, the conference committee reserves the right to take any action the committee deems appropriate, including removing the participant from the conference.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-report-unacceptable-behavior">How to Report Unacceptable Behavior&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the event of unacceptable behavior, participants may wish to inform a person in authority. During ACM REP, participants should reach out to one of the General or Program Chairs (see list below). These individuals can provide information about the process for handling complaints or handling immediate onsite needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
There may be cases (such as those involving Title IX issues in the United States and venue- or employer-specific policies) where an on-site person who is informed of harassment will be required to file a complaint.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>General Chair: Alex Voulimeneas&lt;br>
Program Chairs: Georgios Portokalidis &amp;amp; Soham Chakraborty&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This code of content was adapted from the &lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/about-acm/policy-against-harassment" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Policy Against Harassment at ACM Activities&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://cscw.acm.org/2019/code-of-conduct.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ACM CSCW 2019 conference code of conduct&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/diversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/diversity/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>ACM REP is committed to Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion in Computing and Reproducibility.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following &lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/diversity-inclusion/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the model set forth by the overall ACM community&lt;/a>, the ACM REP community encompasses the wide range and diverse set of professionals working on reproducibility and computing, from educators and researchers to software and hardware developers, system engineers, project managers, and data scientists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As noted by the ACM, &amp;ldquo;Diversity is achieved when the individuals around the table are drawn from a variety of backgrounds and experience, leading to a breadth of viewpoints, reasoning, and approaches [&amp;hellip;] Equity is achieved by supporting the participation of marginalized communities in computing as well as by promoting impartiality and fairness within the procedures, processes, and distribution of resources and systems [&amp;hellip;] [and] Inclusion is achieved when the environment is characterized by behaviors that welcome and embrace diversity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ACM REP is committed to creating an environment that welcomes new ideas and perspectives, and where hostility or other antisocial behaviors are not tolerated. Conference organizers welcome participation and contribution from participants representing different ages, races, genders and sexual orientation, nationality, physical ability, thinking style and experiences to enhance the overall richness in providing quality programs and services for the global community. We also recognize the need to make services, activities, events, etc. more inclusive for individuals with disabilities. We are open to make accommodations and arrangements so that all those interested can participate fully in our events and activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Health &amp; Safety</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/health/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-warning">
&lt;div>
Under construction &amp;ndash; Will be completed soon. The text below is just a placeholder.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We are delighted to welcome attendees to our meeting at INRIA, Rennes University, while also acknowledging continued concerns about the spread of COVID and other health and safety issues. Our team is monitoring the latest guidance and regulations, and our policies align with public health orders. We will follow venue and local regulations regarding masking, distancing, and related health measures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proof of COVID-19 vaccinations or a recent negative COVID-19 test result is currently not required for this event. However, If you are feeling sick or test positive for COVID, do not attend the meeting. We are relying on the responsible behavior of our attendees. We encourage but do not require the wearing of masks by attendees. Masks will be made available at the conference venue. Note that for all hospitality related activities, attendees will have the option to eat meals or partake in coffee breaks outdoors if they desire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If there are any changes in vaccination and/or masking requirements, participants will be emailed prior to the meeting and new requirements will be posted on this page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We kindly ask that attendees please consult and follow TBD guidelines for quarantine and isolation and travel (as they may change) prior to traveling for the meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the meeting, participants are encouraged to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Monitor for symptoms of COVID each morning before coming to the meeting.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consider bringing a rapid COVID test kit in case you experience symptoms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wear a high-quality mask&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you experience symptoms of COVID and/or test positive for COVID while attending ACM REP, you are strongly requested to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Notify colleagues that they may have been exposed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adjust your accommodations and travel plans to follow TBD guidelines for quarantining.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refrain from attending any meeting events.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Housing</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/housing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/housing/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hotels">Hotels&lt;/h1>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning">
&lt;div>
Under construction &amp;ndash; Will be completed soon.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Registration</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/registration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/registration/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Registrations will be online only and will close on July 25, 2025. &lt;strong>On-site registrations will not be available&lt;/strong>.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul class="cta-group">
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://web.cvent.com/event/2da7dd28-2938-4ea7-b3e4-4a27b6c3c2e8/summary" class="btn btn-primary px-3 py-3">Registration closed&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="registration-fees">Registration fees&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ACM Full member&lt;/strong>: 500 USD (late: 600 USD)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ACM Student Member&lt;/strong>: 250 USD (late: 300 USD)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Full Non-member&lt;/strong>: 600 USD (late: 720 USD)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Student Non-member&lt;/strong>: 300 USD (late: 360 USD)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dinner reception&lt;/strong>: 90 USD (late: 110 USD)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In-person registration includes: access to all sessions and tutorials, breaks and lunches on each day. Please note that dinner reception requires a separate ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A limited number of free student registrations are available on request to attend the
conference virtually. We particularly encourage people from underrepresented
groups to contact us.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="important-dates">Important Dates&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;span style=color:grey>Early-bird registration close: July 7&lt;/span>&lt;br>
&lt;span style=color:grey>Author registration close: July 15&lt;/span>&lt;br>
&lt;span style=color:grey>Registration close: July 25&lt;/span>&lt;br>
Conference: &lt;span style=color:blue;font-weight:bold>July 29-31, 2025&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="terms-and-conditions">Terms and Conditions&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="authors">Authors&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For each article accepted at ACM REP 2025, it is required to have at least one of the authors registered at the conference, with the commitment to present it at the conference - online presentations are accepted but require full on site registration as well. Paper without a full registration will be withdrawn from the program and the proceedings. The deadline for author registration is July 15, 2025.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="students">Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Student fees are applicable only to full-time students. Students must be able to provide a proof of their student status (student ID card or certificate).&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="cancellation-policy">Cancellation Policy&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If a registrant is unable to attend an event for any reason they may substitute, by arrangement with the conference organizers, someone else from the same institute/organization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tutorials</title><link>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/tutorials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acm-rep.github.io/2026/tutorials/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="improving-fairability-of-your-research-outcomes-with-ro-crates-and-bioschemashttpsphilreeddatagithubioacmrep25">&lt;a href="https://philreeddata.github.io/acmrep25/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Improving FAIRability of your research outcomes with RO-Crates and Bioschemas&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When:&lt;/strong> July 29th 2025, 9am&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Where:&lt;/strong> Allard 121, in-person presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Authors:&lt;/strong> &lt;u>Phil Reed&lt;/u> (The University of Manchester) and Abigail Miller (The Jackson Laboratory)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> RO-Crate is a lightweight method to package research outputs along with their metadata. Bioschemas provides metadata schemas to add structured metadata to webpages on Life Science. Schemas.science extends this provision into non-bio domains.
The combination of RO-Crates, Bioschemas and schemas.science make resources easy to navigate by machines, provide an unambiguous way for machines to access FAIR metadata and content in a single request, and reduce content-negotiation hassle that can give unpredictable results.
This combination is of benefit for researchers and data providers whenever they want to improve FAIRability of their resources as they can support RO-Crate imports and align with Bioschemas specifications, making FAIR-compliant digital objects achievable with existing technologies such as Web Linking over HTTP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits of adopting RO-Crates are evident in a diverse range of applications. For example, Five Safes RO-Crate &lt;a href="https://w3id.org/5s-crate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://w3id.org/5s-crate/&lt;/a> specifies a profile of RO-Crate for the purpose of workflow execution in a distributed trusted research environment (TRE). The TRE-FX Project (delivered with HDR-UK) is providing safe, federated access to TREs, using the Five Safes RO-Crate standard.
Following a Bring Your Own Resource hands-on style, in this tutorial we will showcase how to use RO-Crates, and Bioschemas to improve FAIRability and will accompany attendees to apply the technologies to their own resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="workflow-mini-apps-evaluating-performance-reproducibility-in-scientific-workflows">Workflow Mini-Apps: Evaluating Performance Reproducibility in Scientific Workflows&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When:&lt;/strong> July 29th 2025, 9am&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Where:&lt;/strong> Allard 113, remote presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Authors:&lt;/strong> &lt;u>Ozgur Kilic&lt;/u> (Brookhaven National Laboratory), Tianle Wang (Brookhaven National Laboratory), Matteo Turilli (Brookhaven National Laboratory), Mikhail Titov (Brookhaven National Laboratory), Andre Merzky (RADICAL-Computing Inc.), Line Pouchard (Sandia National Laboratories), and Shantenu Jha (PPPL, Princeton University)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> Scientific workflows have become indispensable for managing complex computational tasks in high-performance computing (HPC) environments. However, their increasing complexity, scale, and heterogeneity often hinder reproducibility. Workflow mini-apps address these challenges by offering simplified yet faithful representations of complex workflows, enabling easier development, testing, and optimization. This three-hour tutorial introduces participants to workflow mini-apps and demonstrates their practical application to enhance reproducibility. The tutorial comprises three main segments:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Introduction to Workflow Mini-Apps: Participants will learn what workflow mini-apps are, their role in addressing the reproducibility crisis in scientific computing, and the balance between simplicity and fidelity in their design.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Building Workflow Mini-Apps (Interactive Session): Using the wfMiniAPI, an open-source Python and C++ library, participants will interactively construct executable mini-apps. They will learn how to emulate key computational kernels and workflows components, tuning parameters to match performance profiles of original workflows.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Executing and Analyzing Mini-Apps (Interactive Session): Participants will run their constructed mini-apps on HPC resources, collect performance metrics, and analyze reproducibility. Hands-on exercises will highlight portability across platforms and demonstrate mini-apps&amp;rsquo; utility in capturing essential characteristics of original workflows at a significantly reduced computational cost.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This tutorial targets an introductory to intermediate audience familiar with basic Python programming and HPC concepts. By the conclusion, participants will be equipped to leverage workflow mini-apps to simplify the reproducibility and portability challenges of scientific computing workflows, aligning closely with the themes and goals of ACM REP 2025.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="from-your-source-code-to-a-reproducible-online-demonstration">From your source code to a reproducible online demonstration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When:&lt;/strong> July 29th 2025, 1:30pm-5pm&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Where:&lt;/strong> Allard 121, in-person presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Authors:&lt;/strong> &lt;u>Miguel Colom&lt;/u> (Centre Borelli, ENS Paris-Saclay)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> This is a short hands-on tutorial on how to arrive at a complete reproducible research article, with a special focus on building a complete online demonstration of a particular method. The techniques explained and the recommendations given are general and applicable to any journals or platforms. We&amp;rsquo;ll focus more on the practical aspects of the source code and the online interface for the online demo. Eventually, the objective of this practical tutorial is to show that many of the recommendations on computation reproducibility have strong reasons why they should be followed, and with the tools that currently exist today it is straightforward to implement them and reach good reproducibility and replicability in computational sciences. The participants are expected to finish this tutorial with an interactive online demonstration of their proposed methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="computational-reproducibility-with-scientific-workflows-analysing-viral-genomes-with-nextflow">Computational Reproducibility With Scientific Workflows: Analysing viral genomes with Nextflow&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When:&lt;/strong> July 29th 2025, 1:30pm-5pm&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Where:&lt;/strong> Allard 113, remote presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Authors:&lt;/strong> &lt;u>George Marchment&lt;/u> (Université Paris-Saclay), Sarah Cohen-Boulakia (Université Paris-Saclay), Frédéric Lemoine (Institut Pasteur)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In an era of generation of large datasets and complex scientific analyses, ensuring the reproducibility of data analyses has become paramount. Workflow management systems have emerged as a key solution to this challenge, offering structured, automated, and scalable frameworks for handling data processing tasks, allowing for the development of scientific workflows. However, while they are becoming more popular, workflow management systems have not yet gained wide adoption within the scientific community, largely due to established practices and the perceived high learning curve associated with their use.
This tutorial aims at demonstrating the critical role of workflow management systems in implementing reproducible data analyses, with an emphasis on their capacity to encapsulate heterogeneous code, manage software environments, scale with the data size, and leverage heterogeneous computational resources efficiently. To do so, we will use the Nextflow workflow system and a viral genome sequence reconstruction pipeline as a use case. This will demonstrate the fundamentals of Nextflow and illustrate how it can be used to easily implement, execute, and share a simple workflow.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>